EL AYADI FATIMA EZZAHRA

Data Scientist Diplômée d'un Master en Système d'Information et Systèmes Intelligents, passionnée par le NLP, le Deep Learning et le Machine Learning. Je cherche à démarrer ma carrière dans ce domaine, avec des compétences solides en programmation (Python, Java, R) et une expérience dans le développement de modèles d'IA. Je suis prête à apporter ma passion pour l'innovation et mon expertise en IA à une équipe qui encourage la créativité et la résolution de problèmes. elayadifatista@gmail.com in fatima-ezzahra-el-ayadi **(+212 695215922** Salé, Maroc **EDUCATION COMPÉTENCES** Institut National de Statistique et d'Economie Appliquée Langages de Programmation : **===** 2022 – 2024 Rabat, Maroc PYTHON, JAVA, C, R, PHP, JAVASCRIPT, MATLAB, Diplôme Master en Système d'Information et Systèmes Intelligents SCALA. Faculté des Sciences Intelligence Artificielle: **===** 2021 – 2022 Rabat, Maroc NLP/NLG (LANGCHAIN, HUGGINFACE, LLMS), MACHINE Diplôme Licence Fondamentale en Sciences Mathématiques et Informatique LEARNING (SCIKITLEARN), (TENSORFLOW, KERAS). Ecole Supérieur de Technologie

2019 – 2021

• DUT en Administration Réseaux Informatiques

Baccalauréat en Sciences Mathématiques A

2019

₱ Fnideq, Maroc

Salé, Maroc

EXPERIENCE

ONCF, Stage de Fin d'Etude

Février 2024 – Août 2024

- Développement d'une application basée sur l'IA pour la gestion automatisée des Technicentres Ferroviaire.
 - Mise en place d'un modèle YOLO de détection d'objets en temps réel pour améliorer la sécurité et automatiser la gestion des technicentres.
 - Conception d'une application web pour le suivi en temps réel des activités d'un technicentre, y compris la détection des équipements de protection individuelle (EPI) et des engins de manutention, ainsi que leur suivi par DeepSort, la surveillance des zones dangereuses, et la détection des trains et de leur numéro de série via OCR.
 - Automatisation des alertes et du reporting grâce à l'IA pour améliorer la sécurité et l'efficacité

Préfecture de Salé, Stage d'application

Avril 2021 - Juin 2021

Salé, Maroc

• Optimisation et sécurisation d'un réseau local, avec configuration et simulation sur GNS3.

PROJETS

Generative AI Chatbot:

2023

• Création d'un Chatbot pour les Documents Réglementaires de la Douane Basé sur Plusieurs PDFs

NLP - Machine Learning:

• Développement d'un Système de Recommandation basé sur le contenu des offres d'emplois

Computer Vision:

2023

• Détection d'Âge à l'aide de Modèles de Deep Learning VGG16, ResNet et Inception - Benchmarking

Big Data:

2023

• Plateforme de Big Data pour la Transparence Parlementaire.

Analyse des Retours Clients d'une Banque :

• Data Warehouse pour les Retours Clients d'une Banque avec des techniques du Data Mining

2023

Développement d'une Poubelle Intelligente par IOT.

Data Warehouse pour la Gestion des Notes :

= 2022

• Extraction, Transformation et Chargement des Données de Transaction dans un Dépôt de Données Centralisé pour l'Analyse et les Rapports.

Data Analysis:

2022

Analyse de l'Évolution par Nationalité des Arrivées des Touristes aux Postes Frontières Marocains entre 2012 et 2020 en Utilisant l'AFC.

• Conception et Développement d'une Application de Chat Dynamique en utilisant PHP, JavaScript, MySQL et Bootstrap.

DEEPLEARNING

Frameworks et outils pour le déploiement :

DOCKER, FLASK, FASTAPI.

Développement WEB :

HTML, CSS, XML, PHP, JAVASCRIPT, REACT.JS, BOOTSTAP

Base de données :

SQL, PL/SQL, NOSQL, MYSQL, POSTGRESQL, ORACLE.

WEB MINING:

SELENIUM, BEAUTIFULSOUP, SCRAPY.

OCR:

TESSERACT, PaddleOCR.

Tracking:

DeepSort.

Big Data:

HADOOP, CLOUDERA, HIVE, MAPREDUCE.

Business Intelligence :

POWER BI, TALEND, TABLEAU.

MLOps:

MLFLOW.

DEVOPS:

GIT/GITHUB, LINUX.

Modélisation :

UML. MERISE.

AGILITY:

SCRUM JIRA

CERTIFICATIONS

Generative AI Certified Professional **ORACLE**

Neural Networks and Deep Learning Stanford University

Supervised Machine Learning: Regression and Classification Stanford University

Talend Data Integration Certification Preparation training Talend

Data Visualization with Python

Coursera (Powered By IBM)

Python for Data Science, Al & Development Coursera (Powered By IBM)

LANGUES

- Français: Langue courante
- Anglais : Compétence professionnelle
- Arabe : Langue natale

CENTRES D'INTÉRÊT

Sport, Gaming

EL AYADI FATIMA EZZAHRA

Data Scientist

Graduated with a **Master's degree in Information Systems and Intelligent Systems**, passionate about **NLP**, **Deep Learning**, and **Machine Learning**. I am looking to start my career in this field, with **strong programming skills (Python, Java, R)** and experience in **developing AI models**. I am eager to bring my passion for innovation and my AI expertise to a team that encourages creativity and problem-solving.

elayadifatista@gmail.com

in fatima-ezzahra-el-ayadi

Sale, Morocco



EDUCATION

National Institute of Statistics and Applied Economics

2022 - 2024

Rabat, Morocco

• Master's Degree in Information System and Intelligent Systems

Faculty of Sciences

2021 - 2022

Rabat, Morocco

Bachelor's Degree in Mathematical and Computer Sciences

Higher School of Technology

2019 – 2021

Sale, Morocco

DUT in Computer Network Administration

Mathematics Sciences Baccalaureate

Fnidek, Morocco

WORK EXPERIENCE

ONCF, End of Study internship

Feb 2024 - Aug 2024

- Development of an Al-based application for the automated management of Railway Technicentres.
 - Implementation of a YOLO object detection model in real-time to enhance safety and automate the management of technicentres.
 - Conception of a web application for **real-time tracking** of technicentre activities, including the detection of personal protective equipment (PPE) and handling equipment, as well as their tracking with DeepSort, monitoring of dangerous zones, and train detection with OCR for serial numbers.
 - Automation of alerts and reporting using AI to improve safety and operational efficiency.

Prefecture of Salé, Internship

Apr 2021 - Jun 2021

Sale Morocco

Optimization and securing of a local network, with configuration and simulation on GNS3.

PROFESSIONAL & ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Generative AI Chatbot:

2023

Build a Chatbot for Customs Regulatory Documents Based on Multiple PDFs

NLP - Machine Learning:

2023

Development of a Job Offer Recommendation System.

Computer Vision:

= 2023

- Age Detection using Deep Learning Models VGG16, ResNet, and Inception Benchmarking 2023 Big Data:
- Big Data Platform for Analyzing Parliamentary Data and Government Engagement KPIs **Customer Feedback Analysis of a Bank:**
- Data Warehouse for Customer Feedback of a Bank using Data Mining Techniques.

置 2023

• Development of a Smart Trash using IoT

Data Warehouse for Grades Management:

₩ 2022

 Extracting, Transforming, and Loading transaction data into a Centralized data repository for Analysis and Reporting.

Data Analysis:

2022

 Analysis of the Evolution by Nationality of Tourist Arrivals at Moroccan Border Posts between 2012 and 2020 Using FCA.

IOT:

- Conception and Development of a Dynamic Chat Application using PHP, JavaScript, MySQL, and Bootstrap.

TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES:

 PYTHON, JAVA, C, R, PHP, JAVASCRIPT, MATLAB, SCALA.

ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE :

NLP/NLG (LANGCHAIN, HUGGINFACE, LLMS), MACHINE LEARNING (SCIKITLEARN), (TENSORFLOW, KERAS). DEEDI FARNING

FRAMEWORKS AND TOOLS FOR DEPLOYMENT:

DOCKER, FLASK, FASTAPI.

WFR DFV ·

HTML, CSS, XML, PHP, JAVASCRIPT, REACT.JS, BOOTSTAP

Database :

SQL, PL/SQL, NOSQL, MYSQL, POSTGRESQL, ORACLE.

WEB MINING:

SELENIUM, BEAUTIFULSOUP, SCRAPY.

OCR:

TESSERACT, PaddleOCR.

Tracking:

DeepSort

Big Data:

HADOOP, HDFS, CLOUDERA, HIVE, MAPREDUCE.

BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE:

POWER BI, TALEND, TABLEAU.

MLOps:

MLFLOW.

DEVOPS:

GIT/GITHUB, LINUX.

MODELING:

UML. MERISE.

AGILITY:

SCRUM JIRA

CERTIFICATIONS

Generative AI Certified Professional **ORACLE**

Neural Networks and Deep Learning Stanford University

Supervised Machine Learning: Regression and Classification Stanford University

Talend Data Integration Certification Preparation training Talend

Data Visualization with Python

Coursera (Powered By IBM)

Python for Data Science, AI & Development Coursera (Powered By IBM)

LANGUAGES

• Frensh : Advanced

English: Professional proficiency

Arabic : Native language

HOBBIES

Sport, Gaming